[Music]
it's
valentine's day valentine's day
and because i my wife and she is an epic
person in general
i thought i'd make a very special
valentine's ice cream i mean she's
decorated the tub so she already knows
it's coming but you know
why not so what is this
valentine's day ice cream gonna be well
valentine's flavors
you know strawberry raspberry you've got
kind of chocolates things like that
this is a ruby chocolate ice cream base
which we're gonna put a little fudge
flecks in
we were gonna put truffles in it but we
decided to
go with fudge actually and we're gonna
just put a little bit of chambord in
there
um that raspberry flavor will help with
the strawberry swell that will finish
this one off
so anyway i hope you have a go at this
one and we're just gonna get stuck in
and make it
to make the fudge just put your
condensed milk and your chocolate
into a bain-marie heat that up nice and
slowly until it's all fully combined
then quite simply put it in the
container put it in the fridge
let it set and then you can chop it up
into whatever size you need
now for this we're gonna grate it and
put it straight back in the freezer this
stuff will melt
really really quickly so make sure you
act fast and get it back in the freezer
as quick as you can
now i went to the supermarket to try and
buy fresh strawberries but they're out
of season here in england at the moment
and the supermarket had none on the
shelves whatsoever
so instead i bought a really nice high
quality jam and we're going to use that
to create this strawberry as well so to
do that we're going to take
some of it and sieve the
large lumps out i don't want this to be
all bitty
and lots of strawberry parts in there so
we're just gonna
run this for a sieve and make sure it's
nice and smooth
so now the next stage is to just add a
touch of the chambord again we're not
trying to
bring a raspberry flavor to this
but this is obviously alcohol so if
you're making this for children
you might want to take this out but
you're literally just going to put
a teaspoon of the chambord in there no
more than that
and what that will do is just emphasize
that strawberry flavor
but also make sure that strawberry swirl
stays really lovely and soft and doesn't
freeze solid in the ice cream
[Music]
this ice cream is really simple just put
your milk
your sugar and the ruby chocolate into a
part on the hob
and just gently heat it melt it up you
don't need a specific temperature
just get it so that the milk is just
starting to steam
once that's done and all lovely and
combined put it into
a container and put it in the fridge
ideally overnight but a minimum four
hours
so our base has been in the fridge
overnight and 20 minutes ago
as normal i took the base out and added
three tablespoons
of one percent milk powder
that will just help make the base nice
and creamy and it will give it a little
bit more shelf life in the freezer
so what we're going to do now is just
add the last little touch of cream
a very small amount of chambord so we're
going to add about one tablespoon in
here
and again this isn't for raspberry
flavor this is just to help
bring out the flavors of the ruby
chocolate and then we're going to put it
in
our ice cream machine turn it for about
20 minutes but obviously your machine
will most probably differ
and then once it's ready we're gonna
start loading in the tub
[Music]
so here we are next day i'm going to get
this ice cream
straight out the freezer and serve some
up now
obviously this is a valentine's day ice
cream but you can make this anytime this
is incredible all the ingredients are
available
all through the year so you don't have
to just limit this to a valentine's day
but do something nice for your partner
whatever it is that they like take the
time
to you know make a bit of an effort for
them so my wife loves ice cream as much
as i do well almost as much as i do
so let's let's see what it looks like
let's see if it's any good
i mean you must agree the tub is amazing
so again my my wife does these tubs i
tried one and it was awful so
she has the job of decorating on the
tubs from now on so this is straight out
the freezer
it's just shy of 24 hours and
hopefully it looks great in the top
let's it's got a good scoop on it nice
and soft not too soft though i'm
reluctant to add
alcohol to ice cream unless you're
making it
you know alcoholic for a reason you
won't find me adding
you know vodka to to an ice cream just
because you want it soft there are much
better ways of making a decent quality
ice cream than just shoving alcohol in
it
but this one's got a really nice scoop
on it
it's got a great pink color
[Music]
i think you'll agree the color soft pink
really nice the fudge flecks
now we tied with the idea like i said of
putting you know fudge-based truffles
in there but they would have frozen too
hard and then
it just wouldn't have been a nice kind
of thing to eat so shaving that fudge
you get a little bit in every bite let's
um let's see what it tastes like
[Music]
the texture of the ice cream it's
incredible it it's
really soft luxurious kind of velvet
kind of texture to it
the fudge flakes they're not too hard
not too soft they're just right a
little change of texture there with the
fudge you get a very very small
hint of that fudge come through at the
end which is just what you want
strawberry sauce boosted that strawberry
flavor with that chambord
so that really comes forward first once
that strawberry flavor just starts to
teeter off you get that ruby chocolate
flood on through so
it's a really really good combination of
flavors and i highly recommend that you
try this
i'll put the recipe in the description
below but
if for some reason you want to change
something up just just do it experiment
that's what ice cream is all about so
there you go
the valentine's day ice cream slightly
boozy but not too bad if you've got if
you're making this for kids
just take that out yeah it won't make
any difference to the overall effect of
the ice cream
you'll lose a little bit of that
strawberry punch but you know be
absolutely fine
i do hope you've enjoyed this one my
wife and i are probably going to put a
movie on and take the rest of this tub
and chill out and enjoy the night but
our next video
is all about the mcdonald's shamrock
shake and the mcflurry so i hope you
stick around and watch that one but for
now
please remember to like and subscribe
and we'll see you next time
thanks very much